

Dubai

0525860502

jane.vercel.app/

github.com/muchirijane

### **Summary**

Jane Muthoni Muchiri is a Front End Developer who started her journey by self-teaching from the start with Html in June 2020. After designing websites and mobile apps her interest in coding and problem solving increased which led to her current path. She is also a technical writer in Dev. to, where she is also a moderator and best Author 2020. Inspiring others and helping code newbies to start their journey in tech is her passion.

Video Intro: Introducing myself, Why I started programming and What cool project I have worked on recently.

# **Skills**

Languages: JavaScript (ES6 & ES5), HTML, CSS (CSS 3), SASS

Frameworks/Libraries: React Js, Gatsby Js, Next Js, Material UI, Styled-Components, npm

Tools: Git, Visual Studio, Web Storm, Figma, Adobe XD

# **Technical Projects**

PURPLE NOTE APP / GitHub link / Preview site / Firebase note app

### React-js - Material UI - Firebase Cloud - Javascript- Html - CSS

- Created the User Interface with Material UI and included Responsive design.
- Used React router for redirects to let the user go to different pages of the app.
- Implemented a form for the user to create details about the notes which includes selecting a category. Storing the notes in firebase cloud and fetching live data to display on the website in real-time.

AIRBNB CLONE WEBSITE / Backend with Sanity IO / Github Link / Preview site

#### Next-js - React-js - Sanity io - Styled-components - Javascript

- Created backend data by using schemas to structure the data in Sanity Io.
- Added important data about each property like Title, description, location, multiple images, reviews, hosts and reviewers. Fetch data from sanity and use Next Js server-side render props to get data.
- Added Styled- components to styled the data that included text and images. Implemented Responsive design to different devices like phones, tablets, laptops and computers.

PRODUCT AGENCY WEBSITE / Github Link / Preview site / Open Source

#### Next js - React js - Material UI | MUI - JavaScript

- Created an Open source project for the code newbie community.
- Worked with global developers to successfully develop the website from the initial stage.
- Reviewed and Merged pull requests from community contributors. Handled any Git conflicts and managed the different git branches. Which was a 90% success rate.

# Work experience

# Junior Front end developer/ Designer

January 2021 - November 2021

Moshcode Holding Limited

- Worked with designers to sketch and create low fidelity mockups for the websites. Build High fidelity website mockups in Figma or Adobe XD and prototyping the page animations.
- Developing website with basic HTML|CSS|JS | React | Styled-Components. Adding Animations through |s/CSS libraries like Gsap or Framer Motion.
- Build simple sites with WordPress and Elementor.

#### **User Interface Designer**

November 2019 - August 2021

Moshcode Holding Limited

- Analyzing competitive research from popular companies to get insight into a successful Application.
- Creating sketches with pen and paper or using Balsamiq. Creating Low-fidelity and high fidelity mockups on Figma or Adobe XD. Adding prototypes to visibly see the app navigation from one screen to another.

• Exporting the App screens to zeplin and design system to hand off to developers. Plus handling over 60 clients from the initial stage to the final hand-off stage.

#### Education

### **React, Redux and React Hooks**

August 2021 - present

Academind

• Build a basic budget App that you can add your expenses and see and chart for all your items added. Learned about React hooks like useState and useEffect. Pass props from one component to another.

### FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design

July 2020 - August 2020

• Covered topics like: Basic Html5, CSS3, Applied Visual Design, Applied Accessibility. Learned about Responsive Web Design Principles, CSS FlexboX, CSS Grid. Built Responsive Web Design Projects: Tribute page, Survey Form, Landing Page, Documentation page and portfolio page.

## **Degree in Public Relations (Mass Communication)**

2014 - 2018

Jomo Kenyatta University

Majored in Public Relations and minored in Journalism

